Mauaa Datta



mauaa.datta@gmail.com



+91 91767 22453



https://mauaadatta.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

I am a seasoned front end developer with 6+ years industry experience who loves to bring visual design to live. I enjoy building beautiful and functional web applications.

My skill set includes HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript and Angular. I have gained expertise in responsive design. With every line of code, I try to make application more lively and interactive.

Experience



Senior Frontend Developer

Koder

Jun 2019 - Present (1 year 9 months +)

- 1. Worked on building a learning portal called 'U' which allows different instructors to create free/paid courses and teach students. Students can find a variety of courses to enrol.
- Worked on building complete responsive pages
- Involved in writing SQL queries and integrating backend with frontend
- Got exposure to data-scrapping using Octoparse
- Worked on enabling stripe enabled payment gateway
- Technologies/Tools: HTML5, SCSS, jQuery, C#, Razor, Octoparse
- 2. Worked for US based payment platform for users
- Worked on building complete responsive pages
- Technologies/Tools: HTML5, SCSS, jQuery, Gulp



Sr UI/UX Developer

Digitate

Apr 2017 - Jun 2019 (2 years 3 months)

Ignio by Digitate is a Tata Consultancy Services venture, an Al based enterprise solution. I have been working as Sr UI developer responsible to translate the design templates into cross platform web application.

https://www.digitate.com/

Key Responsibilities:

- Enabling webpack and its plugins for boosting performance
- Integrating REST APIs with components using angular and typescript
- · Make shareable and reusable components
- · Carving out widgets with maximum defaults and minimum inputs
- · Providing mixins, utilities and properties with help of SASS
- · Creating HTML for the given visual designs
- · Actively discussing design ideas with UX team to enhance user experience

Business Impact:

- · Applied concepts of RWD for the application
- Optimised the CSS resulting in 30% faster loading of application
- Applied optimisation techniques for HTML and Images which brought down the bundle size by 20%

· Created a customer experience and product briefing center with interactive graphics

Ul Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

Jul 2014 - Mar 2017 (2 years 9 months)

https://www.tcs.com/

Worked for Latin America based e-commerce website

Responsibilities:

- Creating HTML for the given visual designs
- · Coordinating with the onsite team about the requirements and deliverable

Building website for NSDC

Responsibilities:

- · Being involved in requirement gathering and design discussions
- Groomed a team of 24 trainees to learn and develop district wise web portals for NSDC

Education



Mumbai University Mumbai

Bachelor of Science - BS, Information Technology

2011 - 2014

Created a web application for a jewellery retailer with ASP .net with C# and SQL

Created a business portfolio for a Fountain and Swimming pool business as a freelancer



CHM College Mumbai

HSC, PCMB

2009 - 2011

Licenses & Certifications



Angular 4 - Lynda.com



Backbone.js foundation - Lynda.com

Skills

HTML5 • css3 • Bootstrap • angular • SASS • JavaScript • TypeScript • jQuery • RWD • Bootstrap

Honors & Awards



Star Performer - TCS

2018

Awarded star performer for creating the customer briefing center under stringent timelines



Short Story Writer - TCS Maitree Club

2017 Stood winner for short story writing contest. https://mauaadatta.blogspot.com/

Topper in College - Birla College 2014